Dorn M. Moore

Baraboo, WI dorn@greenspacegis.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY:

GIS professional with over 20 years of experience bringing spatial knowledge to bear on unique problems. Experienced cartographer in both digital and print realms with training in cartographic theory. I work best in a collaborative, learning environment where the team brings ideas together to create solutions to technology problems. I am looking for an opportunity to bring my technical and creative expertise to enhance how people understand the world around them.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

International Crane Foundation, April 2013 - Present

Geospatial & Information Services Manager - Baraboo, WI

- Create data visualizations to facilitate research and communicate our scientific research to a broad audience. Tool examples include MapBox Js, Node JS, PostgreSQL integration, and D3.
- Provide spatial analysis support to regional research teams including data aggregation and cleaning in R
 or Python to clean data and run analysis and create graphics and visualizations to help researchers
 understand the data and use in publications.
- Create cartographic products for the organization's communications team using Adobe Illustrator.
- Provide guidance and strategy for the use of geospatial tools across the organization. Examples include training interns and staff in using GIS and basic coding skills, evaluating new tools and techniques for fieldwork, provide protocols and standards for using new technology tools for data collection.
- Manage and maintain key research databases including fundamental design and implementation of the back-end PostgreSQL database and integration with GIS tools like ArcGIS and QGIS.
- Act as the organization's IT Manager by evaluating and implementing new technology tools, migrating services (e.g. local server to cloud-based options), basic training for IT security, and managing vendor relationships and managing services provided by contractors including help-desk contractor.

Black Squirrel Technologies, October 2009 - April 2013

Owner/Principal - Baraboo, WI

• Independent IT service company with core competencies in data management, backup, security and disaster recovery for a diverse client base of small businesses, local governments, and non-profits.

The Baldwin Group, October 2006 - September 2009

Spatial Analyst on contract to NOAA Coastal Services Center - Charleston, SC

- Support the human dimensions program with conceptual design of easy to understand geospatial
 products for coastal land managers. Managed implementation of workflow combining census, hazard
 resilience, and landcover change data into simple, county snapshots.
- Provide training and support for conservation partners in the use of geospatial tools including ArcGIS and how they may integrate GIS into their strategic planning and operations.
- Project Manager for multi-partner efforts of regional coastal conservation efforts.

International Crane Foundation, March 1999 - October 2006

GIS and Remote Sensing Analyst - Baraboo, WI

- Develop and maintain several large research databases including back-end design and simple VBA coding inside an Access database to create a spatially enabled user interface for entering and querying data.
- Cartographic and spatial analysis support for projects in North America, China, and Southeast Asia.
- Development of a 40-year land cover delineation and change analysis of the Zambezi Delta using satellite and aerial imagery.

PUBLICATIONS:

- Barzen et. al. "High nest density of Sandhill Cranes in central Wisconsin." *Proceedings of the North American Crane Workshop.* Vol. 13, 2016, pp. 13-24
- Lacy et. al. "Changes in the number and distribution of Greater Sandhill Cranes in the Eastern Population." *Journal of Field Ornithology.* Vol. 86, No. 4, 2015, pp. 217-325.
- Tran et.al. Persistent organic pollutants in wetlands of the Mekong Basin: U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2013–5196, 140 p., http://dx.doi.org/10.3133/sir20135196
- Beilfuss et al. (2000) Land Cover and Land Use Change in the Zambezi Delta. Chapter 2 in *Biodiversity of Zambezi Basin Wetlands Vol. III. Land Use Change and Human Impacts.*, (pp. 31 105)

EDUCATION:

The University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI M.S. Cartography and Geographic Information Systems – 2019

The University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ M.A Geography and Regional Development – 1998

Beloit College, Beloit, WI B.A. Anthropology & Spanish – 1993

SOFTWARE AND SYSTEM EXPERTISE:

- Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop
- Avenza MAPublisher & Geographic Imager
- Azure Cloud services administration
- ESRI ArcGIS Desktop and Pro
- PostgreSQL Database Administration (with PostGIS)
- Full-Stack Developer Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node JS, Express, GitHub
- Geospatial Specific Development Tools: D3, Leaflet, Mapbox GL JS, Turf.js
- Scripting/Programming Languages: Python and R